Krunal Parmar

→ +1 (647) 327-3577 **►** krunal97parmar@gmail.com **I** linkedin.com/in/krunal-97/

🕥 github.com/Krunal-97/ 😩 krunal-97.github.io/MyPortfolio/

SUMMARY

Ambitious Software Developer with 1+ years of development experience in the industry. Proficient in Software development, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Python, REST APIs, and databases. Plus, with an exceptional academic record, and graduated from Centennial College with an Adv. Diploma in Software Engineering Technology-Artificial Intelligence. With this, earned a Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science.

EXPERIENCE

WIMTACH 01/2022 - 07/2022

Software Engineer Intern — JavaScript, ReactJS, Python, Flask, REST APIs, HTML, CSS

Toronto, Canada

- Created a React-based OCR software to identify text from images and translate it to speech for the use of 150+ kids.
- Designed the interactive reusable React components and performed implementation of API integration.
- Implemented REST APIs using Python and Flask, and achieved the accuracy of predictions to more than 90 percent.

Accupoint Software Solutions

11/2019 - 07/2020

Web Developer — JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery

Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

- Collaborated closely with the development team to build the school's website, which automates the management of attendance, students, parents, teachers, and timetables.
- Involved in complete Life Cycle of web applications including Analysis, Architecture, Design, Development, and Testing.
- Contributed with team members using version control systems such as Git and Used JIRA for assigned task tracking.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Typescript, Python, Java, HTML5, CSS3

Frameworks / Libraries: React.js, Node.js, Express.js, React Native, Bootstrap, Flask, pandas, NumPy, SK-Learn

Database: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, MySQL, NoSQL

Other: MERN Stack, SDLC, Cloud(AWS), Docker, API Development, REST, SOAP, Programming, Git, CI/CD, SASS, Agile Methodology, Requirement Gathering, Jira, Asana, SLA, Troubleshooting, Debugging Isuues, QA

Certifications(LinkedIn Leaning): Node.js Essential Training, Become a React Developer, Building RESTful APIs with Flask

EDUCATION

Advanced Diploma in Software Engineering Technology - Artificial Intelligence

01/2021 - 05/2022

Centennial College — GPA: 4.0/4.5

Toronto, Canada

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

08/2015 - 08/2019

Kadi Sarva Vishwavidhyalaya — Grade: Distinction

Gandhinagar, Gujarat, India

PROJECTS

Intelligent Search | JavaScript, React.js, MongoDB, Python, Flask, RESTful APIs | Link to Check out

- Developed a web app to help organizations to search for answers to input questions from uploaded documents.
- Implemented 10+ features of dynamic user and admin dashboards with React, state management, and JWT.
- Built RESTful APIs for CRUD operations, file uploading, and to search answers from trained data.

Incident Management System | JavaScript, Angular.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Node.js, REST APIs | Link to Check out

- Developed a website to help customers to raise the system-related tickets for the admin to resolve.
- Implemented JWT authentication, route guards, audit trail to track the journey of the raised ticket, and REST APIs.

Card Scanner | ReactJS, Python, AWS, AWS Cognito, DynamoDB | Link to Check out

- Created a multi-user website that can upload any card image to an S3 bucket and recognize card details.
- Developed backend APIs for AWS services to identify entities, store card data in the database, and fetch it using Axios.
- Offers capabilities like multi-user login, search all contacts, search by name, and send contact details via email.

Amazon Clone | JavaScript, React.js, Redux, Sass, Firebase | Link to Check out

- Designed an Amazon clone, where users can sign up, add items to the cart, update the cart, remove items from the cart.
- Built interactive reusable components with React.js that saved over 100+ hours of development time per month and managed state with redux. Also, multi-user login, authentication, and website is deployed using firebase.

ACHIEVEMENTS AND EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- * Secured 1st position in the Manage My Groceries Hackathon 01/2022
- * Secured 2nd position in the Reading Partnership Hackathon in collaboration with WIMTACH 12/2021
- * Significantly contributed in a team of 4, and ranked in top 10 among 500 teams (Gov. of India Hackathon) 2017/18